你那份
Your share.
还有护照 我自己出的钱
And a passport. And I paid for it meself.
感觉是应该的
Only seemed fair.
看起来他们对你下了狠手
Looks like they put you through it.
我手里有他们想要的情报
I knew something they wanted to know,
查理 对吧
didn't I, Charlie?
戴尔 老天
Fucking hell, Dale.
你是要我说谢谢吗
You want me to say thank you?
行啊 非常感谢你
Then fuck yes. Thank you.
你想揍我吗 来 给我的脸来一拳
You wanna hit me? Go on. Punch me in the kisser.
是我自己惹的祸
I fucked myself.
但是现在如果我重获自由 那我能去想去的任何地方
But now, if I'm free, then I'm free to go where I wanted
我不会蠢到留在这里和你纠缠
before I was stupid enough to mess around with you.
(新西兰护照)
当该死的新西兰佬
A fucking Kiwi?
我临时只能搞到这个
It was the best I could do on short notice.
好吧
Okay.
想好要去哪了吗
Know where you're gonna go?
是
Yeah.
戴尔 要去寻找自己了吗
Gonna go find yourself, Dale?
不 我要丢掉自己
No. I'm gonna lose myself.
喂
Oi.
你需要去医院吗
You. You need hospital?
不 不去医院
No. No hospital.
我没事
I'm fine.
这是这里最有本事的夜班经理
This is the most capable night manager
而这是克拉巴本地最好 最便宜的旅馆
in this, the best, cheapest hotel in all of Colaba.
帕拉布 伙计 你知道现在几点了吗
Yaar, Prabhu, do you realize what time it is?
我不想这么晚再招待更多的臭白人了
I don't want any more fucking goras this late.
但他们很累
But they're very tired
如果能登记入住会很感激的
and would appreciate being checked into the room.
请收留他们吧
Take them, please.
看在你的份上我才肯做 -那就做吧
I'll do it because it's you. -Then do it.
好的 填吧 -非常感谢
Okay. Fill it in. -Thank you very much.
这个人说他是旅馆客人
This man says he is a hotel guest?
谁
Who?
这个人说他是旅馆客人 是真的吗
This man says he is a hotel guest. Is this true?
是的 他是客人
Yes, he is a guest.
他叫什么名字
What is his name?
稍等 在登记册上 -让我看看
Just a second. It's in the register. -Let me see.
先生 我帮你找 -给我
I'll show you, sir. -Give it to me.
给我看他的C表格
Show me his C-Form.
C表格在这里
C-Form, it would be over here.
那混蛋曾斗殴 但不想去医院
The bastard has been fighting and does not want the hospital.
这样 -快点 怎么这么磨蹭
Oh, yeah? -Come on. Why does it take so long?
发生了什么 那警察是个十足的烂人
What happened? This pandu is a full motherfucker.
如果你不贿赂他 他会送你坐牢 发生了什么
If you don't bribe him, he'll take you to jail. What happened?
我被抢劫了
I got mugged.
他们抢走了一切 连我的鞋都夺走了
They took everything, even my fucking boots.
一切
Everything?
我只需要躺一会儿
I just need to lie down.
带我去看他的房间 马上
Show me his room. Now.
林 没有护照 没有钱... -你在做什么
Lin. No passport, no money... -What are you doing?
这在孟买是个很大的问题
...is very, very big problem in Bombay.
我们必须马上离开 林 快点
We have to go now. Lin, let's go.
快点 -是 先生
Hurry up! -Yes, sir.
就是这个房间
This is the room.
好的
Okay.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
好 水在这里
Okay. Here is water.
我现在明白你为什么 要带着这个厉害的医药箱了
Now I see why you're carrying this impressive medicine box.
你也应该带了不止一双鞋吧
You should also be carrying more than one pair of shoes, na?
最好的药品
Best medicine.
明天第一件事 我会带你去新西兰领事馆
Tomorrow, first thing, I will take you New Zealand consulate.
他们会给你新的护照 还有钱
They will give you new passport, money.
我不能去找官方机构
I can't go to the authorities.
这对我来说不是一个选择
It's not an option for me.
好吧
Okay.
请 过来 吃吧
Please. Come. Eat, na.
你是我的客人
You are my guest,
我的邻居拉克什米烹饪了...
and Lakshmi, my neighbor, she is making...
最美味的煎饼
first-class roti.
谢谢
Thank you.
不错吧
Good, huh?
我的天 好辣
Wow. It is very spicy.
多谢你 为我所做的一切
Dhanayavaad, for everything.
不知道你怎样 但我需要喝点
I don't know about you, but I need a drink.
这是什么意思
What is that?
三周了 我依然不知道 各种摇头都是什么意思
It's been three weeks. I still don't know which waggle means what.
好吧
Okay.
现在这个的意思是 “当然 我很愿意和你喝一杯”
Right now it is meaning, "Certainly, by all means, I'll drink with you."
但也可能是“不要”或是“你好”的意思
But it can also mean "no." Or "hello."
或是“我懂”
Or, "I understand."
甚至可能是“我为和平而来 所以请别伤害我”
Or even, "I am a man of peace, so please do not be hurting me."
这是可以学的 好吗
And you could learn this, huh?
那样你就不会经历这个 这个还有那个了
Then this won't happen, this won't happen, that won't happen.
你先
After you.
哎 悠着点
Oi, take it easy.
真棒
So good.
口感真够顺滑的
Very, very smooth, yaar.
好吧
Okay.
嘿 哥们
Hey, man.
你留着
Keep it.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
没有 只是...
No. Just...
我要是知道这是我的威士忌 而不是你的
If I was knowing this was my whiskey and not yours,
我就不会这么大口地喝了
I would not have been so generous with myself in drinking it, na.
真的
Really?
你在干什么 什... 嘿
What are you doing? Wh-- Hey!
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
这件衬衫今天才洗的 老兄
This shirt was cleaned today only, yaar.
拿着吧
Take it.
给你的
It's for you.
真的
Really?
戴尔
Dale!
该死的告密狗
You fucking dog.
滚回你的老家
Back to where you belong.
有人曾告诉我 梦就是愿望与恐惧相会之处
Someone once told me that a dream is where a wish and fear meet.
当愿望与恐惧是同一样东西时 则称为噩梦
When the wish and the fear are the same, we call the dream a nightmare.
你确定是鲁祖
You sure it was Rujul?
肥胖 穿金戴银
Fat and shiny, a lot of gold.
手指粗短 老二像小蘑菇
Stubby fingers, little mushroom cock.
我听到他的名字了
And I heard his name,
当时瓦利德在为他鼓劲
when Walid was cheering him on.
你确定鲁祖向瓦利德承诺 给他萨嘎尔瓦达贫民窟土地
And you're sure Rujul promised Walid the Sagar Wada slum land?
是的
Yeah.
我们是他们的助兴节目 帮助他们完成交易
We were their entertainment, a way for them to seal their deal.
另一个女孩森妮很清楚情况
The other girl, Sunny, understood it all,
他们是谁 他们在做什么
who they were, what they were doing.
鲁祖和瓦利德完全不在乎 我们听到了他们的对话
Rujul and Walid didn't give a shit if we heard.
(居民楼)
然后森妮消失了 周不放我走
Then Sunny disappeared, and Zhou wouldn't let me leave.
不得不贿赂那个女仆来给你送信
Had to bribe that maid to come tell you.
她死了 对吧 森妮
She's dead, isn't she? Sunny.
如果不是认识你 我也一样
I'd be the same if I didn't know you.
他们都死死地盯着我 我以为他们一定很恨我
They all stared at me with such intensity, that I thought they must hate me.
现在我明白了 他们不过是在看着我的恐惧
Now I know they were simply staring at my fear.
让人们感到恐惧的是他们对自己的了解
It's what people know about themselves that makes them afraid.
不好意思 厕所在哪里
Excuse me. Where's the toilet?
你昨晚怎么又喊又叫的
How much shouting and yelling you were doing last night?
做噩梦了 所以我今早没叫醒你
Bad dreams, na? That is why I let you sleep this morning.
很好 听着 我真的得去...
Great. Listen, I really need to go to the--
嘿 林 这是拉克什米
Hey! Lin, this is Lakshmi.
我们昨晚吃的煎饼是她做的
She made the roti we were eating last night.
噢 嗨 你好 谢谢你 很美味
Hi. Hey. Thank you. Was delicious.
这是什么地方
Where are we?
这是萨嘎尔瓦达贫民区
This is the Sagar Wada jhopadpatti.
我的家
My home.
我们是贱民
We are the not-people,
这些棚屋是我们勉强度日的贱屋
and these hutments are the not-houses where we are not living.
这是谁的
Whose are they?
她的丈夫 他不在了
Her husband. He's gone.
我不能拿走她亡夫的鞋子
I can't take her dead husband's shoes.
不是死了 林先生
Not dead, Linbaba.
只是去迪拜工作了
Gone to Dubai only, for the work there.
谢谢你...
Thank you. Thank you.
我真的需要大便 -我们走吧
I really do need to shit. -Let us go.
快点
Hurry.
合脚吗
It's good?
可以喝吗
You mind?
如果你认为有帮助的话 喝吧
If you think it helps.
反正还能坏到哪去
Can't make it worse.
你说过你想戒酒的
You said you want to quit.
你知道如果你把鲁祖的事 告诉卡德尔拜 会有什么后果吧
You know what'll happen if you tell Khaderbhai about Rujul, right?
我已经出来了
I'm out now.
我们可以对此保持沉默
We could stay quiet.
如果鲁祖要背叛我们 那我过去一年的辛苦都白费了
If Rujul's betraying us, then I've worked the last year for nothing.
你原本会任我死在宫殿里
You would've let me rot in the Palace
如果我不知道威胁你宝贵地皮交易的信息
if I hadn't known something that threatened your precious land deal.
你利用了我
You used me.
你和毛里齐奥 莫德纳有什么区别
How are you any different than Maurizio and Modena?
也许你才是利用人的那个
Or maybe you're the one doing the using.
你根本不在乎鲁祖
You don't give a shit about Rujul.
毒品 我 那两个男的
The drugs, me, those guys,
不过是让你找替罪羊 为自己推脱责任的方式罢了
just a way to pass the buck and take no responsibility for yourself whatsoever.
阿润 你好吗 强尼
How are you doing, Arun? Johnny?
帕拉布
Prabhu.
我去招待他们 -你不用去 我去
I'll help them. -You won't. I'll go.
把桌子清理了
Go clean the table.
你想要些什么吗
Do you want something?
我们俩都要奶茶和煎饼 谢谢
Chai and roti for us both, please.
你好吗
How you going?
来 坐吧
Come. Sit.
坐吧 南堤塔做的是 全孟买最美味的奶茶 相信我
Sit, na. Nandita is making world best chai in all Bombay. Trust me.
好的
Okay.
谢谢你 阿姨 多谢
Arre, thank you, Kaaki. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
这白人是谁
Who's the gora?
他是我新的生意合伙人 -生意合伙人
He is my new business partner. -Business partner?
我们会一起合作旅游生意
We are going to be working together in the tourist business.
帕瓦蒂
Parvati?
来了
I'm coming!
你对她说了什么  -说你是我的好友
What did you say to her? -That you are my good friend.
那是帕瓦蒂 我一定会娶她 林先生
That is Parvati, and I am determined to marry her, Linbaba.
那是你的女友
That's your girlfriend?
我没说她是我的女友
I did not say she was my girlfriend.
这是我们第一次说话
This is the first time we've ever spoken words to each other.
你以前从没和她说过话
You've never spoken to her before?
这是里程碑式的一天
It is a momentous day.
很高兴我在场见证
Well, glad I could be here to see it.
听着 哥们 我得弄清自己的处境
Listen, mate. I need to figure out my situation.
你不能去找官方机构
You can't go to your authorities.
闭嘴... -但你需要钱 对吗
Shut the fuck-- -But you are needing money, yes?
我在想怎么帮你快速弄到钱
I have been thinking to help you get it very fast.
火车票呢 去你村庄的
What about the train tickets? To your village.
还在吧 能转卖吗
You still have them, right? Can we sell them?
很难卖出火车已经驶出车站的票 不行
Very difficult to sell tickets for a train that has already left the station. No.
我觉得最好的主意是成为生意合伙人
I think it is best idea to become business partners.
一起当孟买导游
To be Bombay guides together.
帕拉布 我不会留在这里 -林先生 你想想
I'm not staying, Prabhu. -Just think, Linbaba.
我们会赚大钱 -我只需要找到卡拉
So much money will be coming. -I just need to get to Karla.
请听我说 我们俩都可以... -我不行 帕拉布
Listen to me, please. We could both be-- -I can't, Prabhu.
嘿...
Hey. Hey.
昨晚非常感谢 好吗
Thank you for last night. All right?
你救了我的命 真的
You were a lifesaver. You really were.
但是我不会留在这里谋生计 好吗
But I'm not staying here and hustling, all right?
这是不可能的 好吗
It's just not gonna happen. All right?
好吧 我之后会回来拿我的东西
All right. I'll be back for my stuff later.
卡拉 是林
Karla, it's Lin.
卡拉 你在吗 我得和你聊聊
Karla, you there? I need to talk to you.
发生什么了  -周夫人知道了
What happened? -Madame Zhou figured it out.
他们差点杀死我
They almost killed me.
他们抢了我的钱 护照 一切
They took my money, my passport, everything.
我警告过你这事很危险 -的确 现在我完了
I warned you it was dangerous. -You did, yeah. Now I'm fucked.
那就去找你的大使馆
Then go to your embassy.
我不能
I can't.
那和我有什么关系
How is that my problem?
你说真的
Seriously?
卡拉 我不懂你为什么这个样子
Karla, I don't understand why you're being like this.
我是来寻求帮助的
I'm asking for help.
卡拉 你得帮帮我
Karla, you need to fucking help me.
我没有责任做任何事
I don't need to do anything.
我还有事
I have somewhere to be.
她当真的
Is she for real?
你看上去需要喝一杯
You look like a man who needs a drink.
我知道昨晚你没把所有毒品给我
I know you didn't give me all the dope last night.
现在由我说了算 不是她
Now it's up to me, not her.
卡拉在几里外就能看出来
Karla can spot them a mile away.
看出来什么
Who?
谁可以利用
People she can use.
她没有逼迫我做任何事
She didn't force me to do anything.
不需要逼迫 这是她的天赋
Didn't need to. It's her gift.
卡拉到底有什么特别的
What's so special about Karla anyway?
我和她一样漂亮啊 不是吗
I'm as beautiful as she is, aren't I?
我摸上去的感觉比看上去还要好呢
I feel even better than I look.
别这样
Don't.
莉莎 你不需要这样的
Lisa, you don't have to do that.
也许我想爽一下
Maybe I wanna feel good.
你呢 我们可以一起爽
Don't you? We can feel good together.
莉莎
Lisa.
你嗑嗨了
You're shit-faced.
为什么男人都喜欢贱人
Why do men like bitches?
是真的
It's true.
男人就喜欢对自己不好的女人
They fall over women who treat them like shit.
无法自拔
Can't get enough of it.
这太糟糕了
This fucking sucks.
你以前没试过戒毒
You never tried to quit before?
我喜欢嗑嗨的感觉
I like being high.
我喜欢与现实拉开一点距离
I like there being some distance.
对于现实生活的事 我不擅长
I'm not good with life stuff.
从未擅长过
Never have been.
也许卡拉把这个留下 是因为她知道你会找到
Maybe Karla left that 'cause she knew you'd find it.
见鬼 你说得对
Fuck, you're right.
我磕了这个 她就可以赶我走
I take this, she can throw me out.
你不像外表看上去那么没脑子 林
You're not as dumb as you look, Lin.
我要吐了
I'm gonna puke.
这种感觉要维持多久
How long is it this bad?
几天
Few days.
然后会好转吗
And then it gets better?
会的
It does.
你不会想念吗
You don't miss it?
每天都会
Every day.
卡德尔拜
Khaderbhai.
愿和平与你同在
Salaam alaikum. Alaikumu assalam.
见到你很高兴 请坐
It's good to see you. Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
一切可好 你说情况紧急
Is everything all right? You said it was urgent.
我昨晚去了宫殿
I went to the Palace last night.
如果你不放下执着 你对周的憎恨将永远不会消失
Your hate for Zhou is a wound that will never heal if you keep picking at it.
周扣押了我的朋友莉莎
Zhou was holding my friend Lisa prisoner.
因为莉莎知道的信息
Because of what Lisa knew.
有人背叛我们了
We're being betrayed.
我们合作的领域 一直以来是孟买的日常生意
Our business together has been the usual Bombay dhanda.
贿赂和协定 大家都知道的
Bribes and understandings, what everyone expects.
但我有别的生意 你很清楚
But I have other business. You know this.
出于对你的尊重和喜爱
Out of respect and affection for you,
我从未要求你跨越 我两个世界的界线 卡拉
I've never asked you to cross the line between my two worlds, Karla.
你肯定吗  -如果不肯定 我不会来
Are you certain? -I wouldn't be here if I wasn't.
你必须肯定自己准备好了
I mean, you must be certain that you are ready
接受把这次背叛告诉我的后果
for what telling me about this betrayal means.
如果不把我所知道的告诉你 你会蒙受重创
If I don't tell you what I know, then you'll suffer.
相反 你愿意为我蒙受重创
Instead, you would suffer for me.
你为我做了那么多
You've done so much for me.
我们之间不存在谁欠谁
There is no debt between us.
爱不计较得失 砝码或交换
Love has no accounting or ledger or quid pro quo.
我们投入爱里 是因为无论是否有回报 我们的内心坚持如此
We invest it because our heart insists without any demand of return.
卡拉 这是你仍需要学习的最重要一课
And this is the lesson, above all others, you still need to learn, Karla.
鲁祖阿德卡在和瓦利德沙私会
Rujul Aadekar has been meeting with Walid Shah.
他会接受瓦利德对萨嘎尔瓦达的投标 而不是我们的
He will accept Walid's bid for Sagar Wada, not ours.
这事你最好没搞错
You better not be wrong about this.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不知道人们为何不能更友善
I don't know why people can't be nicer.
是因为一个女孩吗
Was it a girl?
让你第一次尝试海洛因
Turned you on to heroin the first time?
她是谁
Who was she?
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
让我们坠入黑洞的永远是爱
It's always love that sends us down the rabbit hole.
你害怕吗
Are you scared?
我信任你
Trust you.
等我们有钱去印度 我们可以每天这样
Once we have the money to go to India, we can do this every day.
我们一定会玩得爽翻 宝贝
We're gonna have such an amazing time, baby.
帮我个忙好吗 丢了那玩意
Do me a favor? Get rid of that shit.
好的
Sure.
莉莎 嘿
Lisa. Hey.
鲁祖阿德卡是谁
Who's Rujul Aadekar?
就当你没听见过吧
Forget you ever heard that.
告诉我
Tell me.
不 忘了吧
No. Leave that alone.
你在帮我 我也要帮你
You're helping me. I'm helping you.
宫殿之所以能存在 是因为它从来都不选边站
The Palace is allowed to exist because it has never taken sides.
我们将提醒周 她经营生意所依靠的宽宏大量
Zhou will be reminded of the grace under which she operates.
和我说说这个帮了你的男人
Tell me about this man who helped you.
他叫林福特
His name is Lin Ford.
我知道他即将离开 所以我利用他把莉莎弄出来
I knew he was about to leave town, so I used him to get Lisa out.
你一定是信任他 对你来说这不是个简单的举动
You must have trusted him. That is no small thing for you.
我当时很赶时间 他很合适
I was in a hurry. He fit the bill.
他知道鲁祖的事吗
Does he know about Rujul?
他听到名字了 别的没有
He heard the name. Nothing more.
不知道其中的意思
Has no idea what any of it means.
但是一个聪明又有门路的人 也许会四处打听
But a smart and resourceful man might decide to ask.
(雷纳尔多咖啡馆)
好的...回头见 谢谢...
Okay, okay. I'll see you soon. Thank you, thank you.
很荣幸...就像这样 对吗
Pleasure. Pleasure. And we do it like this, yeah?
嘿
Hey.
你的脸怎么了
What happened to your face?
我被打劫了
I got mugged.
天 -我需要新的证件
Wow. -I need new papers.
为什么问我
Why are you asking me?
因为你是我在孟买所认识最厉害的骗子
'Cause you are the biggest crook I know in Bombay.
无意冒犯 -完全不会
No offense. -None taken.
我猜 原因不用和我说
And I can assume, for reasons I need not know,
你不能去找领事馆
that your consulate is not an option?
当然 否则你不会来找骗子
Bien s?r. Or you wouldn't need a crook.
我得买一本护照 你说你认识那个人
I need to buy a passport. You said you know the guy.
阿布戴尔卡达尔可汗 掌控着孟买的假文件生意
Abdel Khader Khan controls the book business in Bombay.
你能安排我见他吗
Well, can you set me up with him?
如果他们把我的护照卖给他了 也许他能卖回给我
If they sold my passport to him, maybe he'd sell it back to me.
林 你读过《教父》吗
Have you read The Godfather, Lin?
我看过电影
I've seen the film.
那就是卡达尔可汗
That is Khader Khan.
这不是可以随随便便安排见面的人
This is not a man with whom you just get set up.
你能给他什么 你说你没钱
What would you offer him? You said you have no money.
一本有用的护照要价是一千美元
A good passport, one worth having, will cost a thousand dollars.
一千美元
A thousand dollars.
拜托 我一定能做些什么
Come on. There must be something I can do.
没有人比你更了解这里
No one knows this place like you do.
我以为我们是朋友
I thought we were friends.
我没有朋友 这种时候就是原因
I do not have friends. Times like this are exactly why.
我必须做些什么
Well, I gotta do something.
你知道 我昨晚是在贫民窟过夜的
You know, I slept in a fucking slum last night.
孟买一半的人都是
As did half of Bombay.
你认识一个叫鲁祖阿德卡的人吗  或是阿第克
Do you know a guy called Rujul Aadekar? Or Ah-dee-kuhr.
是 他是本地政客
Yeah, he's a local politician.
他在宫殿牵涉一些见不得人的勾当 周夫人的地方...
Well, he's involved with some shady shit at the Palace, Madame Zhou's place--
你...不要声...
Just-- Keep your--
也许这条消息会对某些人有价值
Maybe that information would be worth something to someone.
你能四处问问吗  -压低声音
Could you just ask around? -Keep your voice down.
去他的 我需要找回自由 迪迪埃
Fuck that. I want my freedom back, Didier.
我不在乎是否会把周 卡拉她们拉下水 -你能冷静点吗
I don't care if I screw over Zhou, Karla... -Will you calm down?
还有教父 鲁祖 都无所谓 直到我如愿 无论...
...the Godfather, Rujul, whoever the fuck, until I get it. Whatev--
该死 -先生们
Fuck. -Gentlemen.
《肮脏的哈里》 林 我看了录像版本的
Dirty Harry, Lin. I've seen it now on VCR.
不是西部片 但还是很不错
It's not a Western, but very good all the same.
“我开了六枪 还是只开了五枪 ”
"Did I fire six shots, or only five?"
很酷 -祝你好运 林 好吗
It's very cool. -Bonne chance, Lin. Okay?
祝你心想事成
Wish you good luck.
我最喜欢《黄昏双镖客》
For a Few Dollars More is my favorite, yaar.
然后可能是《西部执法者》
And then maybe Josey Wales.
等等 不 我的前三名应该是 《镖客三部曲》
Actually, no, the whole Dollars trilogy would be my one-two-three.
然后《西部执法者》是第四 因为...他演绎的方式实在是...
And then maybe Josey Wales is my fourth, because-- just the way he puts it all--
我们得聊聊
You and me need to have a word.
这家伙是疯子 瞧瞧他
This guy is crazy. Look at him.
等我们摆脱他 抱歉
Let me get rid of him. Apologies.
想都别想 伙计
I'm going nowhere, mate.
我刚被人痛揍
I just got the shit kicked out of me.
在我去帮卡拉把莉莎从宫殿里救出来之后
After I went and helped Karla get Lisa out of the Palace.
什么 莉莎怎么了
What? What happened to Lisa?
你不知道
Oh, you didn't know?
周扣押了她 她状态糟透了
Zhou was holding her prisoner. She's a fucking mess.
抱歉 你必须离开
Sorry. You need to leave.
谢谢
Thank you.
不...
No, no, no, no.
你要去哪 是个玩笑 你要去哪
Where are you going? It's a joke. Where are you going?
我觉得你应该停止干涉我的生意
You know, I think you should stop interfering with my business.
林 莉莎没事吧 她在哪里
Lin, is Lisa all right? Where is she now?
怎么 你以为我会告诉你们两个混蛋
What, you think I'd tell you arseholes?
周的手下抢走了我的钱和护照
Zhou's people took my money and my passport.
在我看来 这都是你们造成的 -嘿...
The way I see it, all of that is on you. -Hey, hey, hey.
如果你是为了个毒虫妓女去搞英雄救美
If you went to play hero for a junkie whore,
那这是莉莎的问题
that is Lisa's problem.
如果你是为了取悦卡拉 那是她的问题
And if you did it to please Karla... That is her problem.
但是你和我之间没有瓜葛
But you and I, we have no relationship.
我什么都不欠你
I owe you nothing.
我觉得你说错了
I think you're wrong about that.
别想就这样离开 -哥们
Don't fucking walk away from me. -Arre, chaps.
没事 不 没关系 -别在这里闹 请坐
It's okay. No, it's okay. -This is not the place. Please, sit down.
你们俩都坐下
Both of you, sit.
你先 -请坐
After you. -Have a seat.
你以为自己是谁
Who the fuck do you think you are?
你突然出现 把自己当成什么人物了
You turn up here, you think you matter?
你知道 只有傻瓜才会 不摸清规则就玩游戏
You know, only a fool plays a game without knowing the rules first,
也不了解其他玩家
or the other players.
莫德纳 我们走
Let's go, Modena.
我想揍扁他那张笑着的俊脸蛋
I wanted to smash his pretty smiling face in.
因为我知道我可以 也因为那感觉一定很好
Because I knew I could and because it would feel great.
但更多是因为我知道他是对的
But mainly 'cause I knew he was right.
帕拉布
Prabhu.
听着 经过了今天上午 如果你让我滚 我不会怪你
Look, after this morning, I wouldn't blame you if you tell me to piss off,
但我必须打个电话 而我没钱
but I need to make a phone call, and I've got no money.
是吗
Yeah?
好的 谢谢你
All right. Thank you.
我能打国际长途吗
Can I make an international call?
当然 林先生
Of course, Linbaba.
3卢比可以打去世上任何地方
For three rupees you can call anywhere in the world.
但有个问题 我以为你没有可以求救的人
But one thing. I thought you had no one to be calling for help.
有一个人欠我人情
There's one person who owes me.
国际长途
ISD.
谢谢 -拨号
Thank you. -Dial.
通了吗
It's okay?
是 -嗨 是我
Yeah? -Hey. It's me.
查理 你在吗 是戴尔
Charlie, you there? It's Dale.
你不该打给我 我们说好了不联络
You shouldn't be calling me. There's no contact, we said.
我知道...哥们
I know. I know, mate.
听着 我需要你寄点钱来孟买
Look, I need you to send me some money to Bombay.
戴尔 欠你的已经还你了
Dale, you got what you were owed.
哥们 你不能就这样打来继续敲诈我
You can't just call and expect to keep sucking on the tit, mate.
我遇到大麻烦了 查理
I'm in serious trouble, Charlie.
这对你来说已经习以为常了吧
Well, it's a bit of a habit with you, eh?
总是四处捅蜂窝
Always got your dick in a vice.
这一次与我无关
This one's nothing to do with me.
与你有关 因为你已经毁了我一生
Yes, it is, because my whole life is fucked because of you.
拜托 查理 请帮帮我
Come on, Charlie. Just help me out, please.
这是你欠我的 -我已经还清了
You owe me. -Not anymore, I don't.
你没有 你欠我
Yes, you do. You fucking owe me.
如果不是我 你会坐穿牢底
You'd be rotting in a fucking prison cell if it wasn't for me.
查理
Charlie.
该死的
Fuck!
林
Lin.
Lin!
林
林 等等 -什么 为什么
Lin, wait! -What? What? Why?
你为什么要帮我
Why you trying to help me?
我和你一点也不熟 你对我毫无了解
I barely know you. You know nothing about me.
因为你是我的朋友
Because you're my mate.
是 朋友...
Yeah, mates. Mates.
朋友只会捅你刀子 相信我
Mates just fuck you over. Trust me.
林 -什么
Lin. -What?
听着 在这里我们一无所有
Listen. Here, we have nothing.
如果大家不互相扶助 那在这里根本无法活下去
This place is not working without everyone helping each other.
林 就像我想帮你一样
Like I want to help you, Lin.
好吗
Okay?
我一整天都对你态度恶劣
I've been a total prick to you all day.
是的
Yes.
我看得出你很不顺
I can tell you're having a not-so-good time.
你也不完全了解自己的处境
Also not fully understanding your situation.
但现在 我认为你已经了解
But now, I think you are understanding.
什么 了解我走投无路  -是的
What? That I'm totally fucked? -Yes.
所以现在你明白了我们可以开始帮你
And so now you're understanding we can start getting you...
“找路”
"unfuck."
“找路” -是的 “找路”
"Unfucked." -Yes, "unfuck."
我们俩合作
With us both working together,
一定能赚得口袋满满 林先生
we will make good money fatafat, Linbaba.
好的 那我们快点开始吧
All right. Then I guess we better get started.
走吧...老大
Chalo. Chalo, boss.
你觉得这个林是什么样的人
What kind of man is this Lin, do you think?
不知道 但卡拉请他帮忙 他也帮了
I don't know. But Karla asked him for help and he gave it.
我接到雷纳尔多咖啡馆的电话
I got a call from Reynaldo's.
他去过那里 在咖啡馆大闹
He was there, making a scene.
他知道的太多 也不懂得闭嘴
He knows more than he should and talks more than I like.
愿和平与你相伴 多谢你前来 部长
Assalamu alaikum. Alaikumu assalam. Thank you for coming, Minister.
这是当然的 你召唤 我就来
Of course. You call, I come.
我注意到你有做功课
You have been doing your homework, I see.
知识就是力量 鲁祖
Knowledge is power, Rujul.
只有结合了金钱和影响力时才是
Only if you combine with money and influence.
在我的情况下 还包括一个政府高位
Or, in my case, a very fine government position.
萨嘎尔瓦达的这些人都知道他们完了
These people in Sagar Wada all know they are fucked.
但是知道这一点并不会给他们赋予力量
But, there's no power in that for them.
你上一次去贫民区是何时
When was the last time you went to one of the jhopadpattis?
去看那里的人
To see the people there.
我刚来孟买时曾在其中一个贫民区待过
When I first came to Bombay, I spent time in one of them.
现在早已消失
It's long gone now,
但我当时所见 现在依然见到的 是那些人不认为自己完了
but what I saw then, and still see now, is they do not believe themselves fucked.
他们没有头脑 也没有教育以培养野心
They do not have the brains nor the education to foster ambition.
有野心的人从不满足于当下 -我们这样的人
Ambitious men are never content. -Men like us?
是的 我的朋友 我们这样的人
Yes, my friend. Men like us.
你显然已经离开贫民区了
You're not in the slum any longer.
是的 但我一直铭记在那里学到的教训
No, but I never forgot the lessons I learned there.
忠诚高于一切
Loyalty is everything.
不知道瓦利德在周的宫殿学到了什么教训
I wonder what Walid learned at Zhou's palace.
我知道你打算背叛我
I know you plan to betray me
把萨嘎尔瓦达卖给瓦利德沙
and sell Sagar Wada to Walid Shah.
我是不是得罪你了
Have I wronged you in any way?
卡德尔拜
Khaderbhai--
你的整个政治生涯都是我赞助的
I financed your entire political career.
我们是朋友
We have been friends.
所以告诉我
So tell me...
我怎么得罪你了
how have I wronged you?
你落后了
You have fallen behind.
你坚持不碰海洛因和性交易生意
Your insistence in staying out of the brown sugar and sex trade
意味着你无法和 瓦利德在萨嘎尔瓦达上竞价
means you cannot compete with Walid's price for Sagar Wada.
所以我没有得罪你
So, I did not wrong you?
我就该少赚钱
I am supposed to make less money
只为了你可笑的道德原则
because of your absurd code of morality?
你应该来找我 我会听你说
Well, you could have come to me. I would've listened.
然后什么都不做
And done nothing.
卡达尔 你变得软弱了
You have become weak, Khader.
莉莎
Lisa.
莉莎 是塞巴斯蒂安
Lisa, it's Sebastian.
你来这做什么
What are you doing here?
我想看看你好不好 是否需要什么
I-- I wanted to see if you're okay, if you needed something.
你怎么知道我在这里
How did you know I was here?
是林 他去雷纳尔多咖啡馆 找毛里齐奥算账
Lin. He came after Maurizio at Reynaldo's.
他很危险 我认为
He's dangerous, that one, I think.
是林救我出来的
Lin's the one who got me out.
那人连我的名字都不清楚 却为了我冒生命危险
Guy barely knows my name, and he risked his life for me.
毛里齐奥知道你来吗
Does Maurizio know you're here?
不知道 -他派你来的吗
No. -Did he send you?
不 莉...
No. Li--
莉莎 我不该让毛里齐奥逼你去那种地方
Lisa, I shouldn't have let Maurizio make you go to such a place.
我应该告诉他的 莉莎 我很抱歉
I should've told him. I'm sorry, Lisa.
此刻我明白你如何看我
I can see how you look at me now.
这是我应得的
And I deserve it.
你懦弱不是你的错
It's not your fault you're weak.
我...爱你
I... love you.
是 但你照顾不了我
Yeah. But you can't look after me.
我...
I...
我想你可能需要一些
I thought you might need some.
是吗
Did you?
还是毛里齐奥让你给我补货 好继续控制我
Or did Maurizio tell you to shoot me up so I fall right back into line?
不 莉莎 毛里齐奥 不知道我来这里 我保证 我...
No. Lisa, Maurizio doesn't know I'm here, I promise. I...
我只希望你快乐 仅此而已
I just want you to be happy. That's all.
他和我 你必须做个选择 莫德纳
Him and me? You're gonna have to choose, Modena.
我选你...莉莎 我永远都会选你 永远
You. You, Lisa. I'd always choose you. Always.
你想要吗 我可以...
Do you want this? I-- I can...
不 我想戒毒
No. I wanna quit.
你说你爱我 那就帮我戒
You say you love me, then help me with that.
莉莎 告诉我怎么做
Lisa. Just tell me how.
这是帕拉布
This is Prabhu.
以我的个人经验 不得不说
From personal experience, I can tell you,
你想要什么 他都能用最好的价格找到
anything you want, he can get you at the best prices.
这是迪特 莎拉和弗朗萨 对吗
This is Dieter, Sarah, and Francois. Right?
是 -很想买上等品质的大麻
Yeah. -Keen to buy some top-quality charas.
很高兴认识你们
Very pleased to meet you.
你们想要多少大麻  -我们要450克
How much charas you are wanting? -We want a pound.
量不少啊
This is a lot of smoking.
你能找到吗
Can you do it?
当然 没问题
Arre, of course, this is no problem.
你们可以去喝啤酒 享受音乐
You can go drink your beers, enjoy the good music.
等我送过来 好吗  -不错
I'll bring it, okay? -Sounds good.
好的 去去就回 -谢谢你
All right. I'll be in in a minute. -Thank you.
林先生 我说过吧 这是门好生意
I told you, Linbaba. Good business.
能赚大钱
Big money for this.
等等
Wait.
什么 想观光 买大麻
What? You wanna see the sights? Buy some charas?
这里有一千美元 之前麻烦你了
There's a thousand dollars in here for your trouble,
还有阿穆达巴的一位联络人和一个地址
and a name and an address in Ahmedabad.
对方会等你
They'll be expecting you.
并给你制作新的护照 钱我出
They'll make you a new passport at my expense.
这是你需要的 对吗
That's what you need, isn't it?
今天上午之后发生了什么
What changed since this morning?
你真的需要我闭嘴 是吧
You really need me to keep quiet, eh?
林 无论你在找什么 在这里是找不到的 以后不可能了
Whatever you're looking for, Lin, it's not here. Not anymore.
我本以为找的是你
I thought maybe you were it.
现在你知道不是了
Now you know different.
大麻交易中你那一半的钱
Your half of charas deal.
不 你留着 我已经得到我需要的了
No, you keep it. I got what I need.
听着 如果你觉得我是混蛋 我理解
Look, I understand if you think I'm a prick,
但我想要一个真正的道别
but I would like a proper goodbye.
我们不会再见了
I will not be seeing you again, na?
是的
No.
林先生 你有一颗善良的心
You have a good heart, Linbaba.
你和卡达尔说了吗  -是的
Did you tell Khader? -Yes.
那么我们害死了一个人
Then we just got a man killed.
这不会困扰你
It doesn't bother you?
我已经做了选择
I made my choice.
我找到了你留下的海洛因
I found the heroin you left behind.
你想知道我做了什么选择吗
You wanted to see what choice I'd make?
然后呢
And?
林说服我别嗑
Lin talked me out of it.
我让他丢掉毒品
I made him throw it away.
我想改变
I wanna change.
他原本会给你带来好的影响
He could've been good for you.
我今晚帮他离开孟买了
I gave him a way out of Bombay tonight.
这是我能给他最好的东西了
It's the best thing I could give him.
夺走一条命 拯救一条命
Take a life, save a life?
这就让一切合理了
Does that make it all okay?
曾经我们总是一起跳舞 记得吗
We danced together all the time, once. Do you remember?
我记得
I remember.
我那时爱着你
I was in love with you.
想要成为你看上去的样子
Wanted to be everything you seemed to be.
但是 其实你也知道
But, then, you know that.
吓我一跳
Fuck me.
我要走了 好吗
I'm leaving. All right?
告诉那个疯女人周我要走了
You tell that mad cow Zhou I'm on my way.
我要离开孟买 不需要这样
I'm leaving Bombay. There's no need for any of this.
去你的
Fuck you!
该死的
Fuck.
这一次我真的想吸取教训
I was trying to learn my lesson for once.
学着聪明点 做我需要做的 为了存活
Be smart and do what I needed to survive.
为了自由
To be free.
(改编自格里高利大卫罗伯茨的 小说《Shantaram》)
字幕翻译:易晗